Guide to the Foster Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Correspondence, Series I
  - John Marshall Foster
    - S-V, fragments, 1886, 1895, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Clara Hess Foster
    - Chan Gek Eng, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Foster, Mr. and Mrs. John B., 1889, 1894-1897 (Box 5, Folder 85-88)
    - Foster, Mrs. John B., 1898-1909 (Box 5, Folder 89-92)
    - Foster Children, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Harriet (Aunt), Illegible Signature, 1898, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Foster, Mr. and Mrs. John B., 1888-1894 (Box 17, Folder 51-56)
    - Foster, Mrs. John B., 1900-1909, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 57-61)
    - Foster, John Hess, 1921, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - Hoist, Mr. and Mrs. Charles A.; Russell, W.E.; Scott, Anna K.; fragment, 1901, 1921, l890, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 63)
    - To Mrs. Thomas, mother of Helen Thomas Foster, 1920 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Children of John and Clara Foster
    - Correspondence, 1894-1958, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 95-98)
  - Helen and Anna Foster
    - Everett, S.B., 1912 (Box 18, Folder 64)
  - Anna Elizabeth Foster
    - Foster, Elizabeth B.; Chang Yong, Flora; Geidt, E.H., 1894-1913, 1968, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 65)
    - Incl. re: death of Anna E. Foster Frank C. Foster, 1916, 1943, 1944, 1968-1974, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 66)
    - Incl: General Letters, 1914, 1921, 1957 1972 (Box 18, Folder 67)
  - John Hess Foster
    - Carey, J.F., 1886 (Box 18, Folder 68)
    - Mr. and Mrs. John M. Foster, Clarence and Frank, 1898-1903 (Box 18, Folder 69)
    - Foster, Elizabeth B., 1916 (Box 18, Folder 70)
    - Incl: War Department, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 71)
    - Incl; Leavens, Dickson H., 1919 (Box 18, Folder 72)
    - Corres. Rec'd, 1920 (Box 18, Folder 73)
    - Incl: Foster, Frank, 1921 (Box 18, Folder 74)
    - Incl: Hume, Edward H., 1922 (Box 18, Folder 75)
    - Incl: Greene, Roger S., and "A Farewell Speech", 1923 (Box 18, Folder 76)
    - Incl: Farnan, Louise W., 1924 (Box 18, Folder 77)
    - Incl: Wells, Clifford W., 1925, 1926 (Box 18, Folder 78-79)
    - Incl: Foster, Frank; Vincent, J.C. (Consulate General) 1926 Sep-`Nov (Box 18, Folder 80)
    - Incl: Foster, Frank; Vincent, J.C.; Nurses' Cooperative Association Changsha, 1926 Dec (Box 18, Folder 81)
    - Incl: Foster, Frank; Bliss, Dayton; Vincent, J.C., 1927 Jan-Feb (Box 18, Folder 82)
    - Incl: Hume, Edward H.; Brown, Charles H., 1927 Mar (Box 18, Folder 83)
    - Incl: Lingle, W.H., 1927 Apr (Box 18, Folder 84)
    - Incl: Foster, John, 1927 May (Box 18, Folder 85)
    - Incl: Leavens, Dickson H., 1927 Jun, Jul (Box 18, Folder 86)
    - Incl: Kiang, K.K.; Wang, K.Y., 1927 Aug-Dec (Box 18, Folder 87)
    - Incl: Tien, Z.M., 1928, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 88)
    - Incl: Monroe, Robert T., 1934 (Box 18, Folder 89)
    - Incl: McCracken, J.C., Greene, Phil, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 90)
    - Incl: Leavens, Dickson H., 1936-1940 (Box 18, Folder 91)
    - Incl: Foster, Anne, 1942, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 92)
    - Incl: Vincent, John Carter, Bureau of National Archives, Department of State, 1944, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 93)
    - Incl: Chang, H.C.1, 1946-1948, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 94)
    - Corres. Rec'd, 1955-1968 (Box 18, Folder 95-96)
    - Incl: Kiwanis Club, 1973, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 97)
    - Incl: Farnam, Louise W., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 98)
    - Incl: Fosters--John T., Randall C., Walter S., Ida L., fragment, 1922, 1947, 1972-1974, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 99)
  - Addendum: John Hess and Helen Thomas Foster
    - Letters to Thomas family in U.S., written enroute to China, from Shanghai and Nanking, 1919 May-Oct (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Letters to Thomas family in U.S., written from Nanking, 1919 Nov-1920 Feb (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
    - Letters to Thomas family in U.S., written from Nanking, Shanghai, 1920 Mar-May (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Thomas family in U.S., written from Nanking, Kuling, 1920 Jun-Aug (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
    - Letters to Thomas family in U.S., written from Changsha, 1920 Dec- 1921 Aug (Box 12, Folder 8-10)
    - Letters to Thomas family in U.S., written from Changsha, 1922 Apr, 1925 Jan (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Journals, Series II
  Scope and Contents
  This series is composed of two sections:
  The journals of John Marshall Foster document the years 1888-1916, with the exception of the second furlough period, 1903-1908. Foster divided the material written between 1888 and May, 1894 into twenty-nine volumes. In April, 1897, Foster started a new series of journals, beginning at volume one. However, the volume indications gradually cease, and beginning in approximately November 1899, new sections are called simply "New Volume" or "New Folio". Several folders of "Miscellaneous Journals", which lack positive date identification, are filed at the end of the section. The journals of John Marshall Foster written between November 19, 1915, and September 4, 1916 have journal entries by Clara Hess Foster on the reverse of the pages. Photocopies have been made for use copies, and the originals are located at the end of the series, labelled "Restricted Circulation". Some typed transcripts of Foster's journals are available in Box 11, Folder 79.
  The journal of Clara Hess Foster, dating from 1915 to 1916, was written on the reverse sides of her husband's journal pages. Photocopies are available for use, and the originals are located at the end of the series.
  - John Marshall Foster
    - "Vol I", 1888 Jan 14- Mar 11 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Vol II", 1888 Mar 12-1888 May 3 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "Vol II", "Vol III", 1888 May 4-1888 May 17 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Vol III", 1888 May 18-1888 Jul 20 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "Vol IV", 1888 Jul 21-1888 Oct 12 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Vol V", 1888 Oct 14-1888 Dec 23 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Vol VI", 1888 Dec 24-1889 Feb 23 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "Vol VII", 1889 Feb 23-1889 Apr 17 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Vol VIII", 1889 Apr 17-1889 Fy 12 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "Vol VIII", 1889 May 14-1889 Jun 28 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "Vol IX", 1889 Jun 29-1889 Sep 19 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "Vol X", 1889 Sep 19-1889 Dec 13 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "Vol X", 1889 Dec 14-1890 Apr 23 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Vol XI", 1890 (Mar 20?)- 1890 Jun 11 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - "Vol XI", 1890 Jun 12-1890 Sep 22 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "Vol XII", 1890 Sep 23-1890 Nov 21 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Vol XIII", 1890 Nov 21-1891 Feb 14 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Vol XIV", 1891 Feb 15-1891 Apr 21 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Vol XV", "Vol XVI", 1891 Apr (19?)- 1891 Jul 21 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - "Vol XVI", 1891 Jul 21-1891 Nov 1 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "Vol XVII", 1891 Nov (27)- 1892 Jan 20 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "Vol XVIII", 1892 Jan 21-1892 Apr 14 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "Vol XIX", 1892 Apr 14-1892 Jul 30 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - "Vol XX", 1892 Jul 30-1892 Oct 29 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - "Vol XXI", 1892 Oct 29-1892 Dec 16 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - "Vol XII, 1892 Dec 16-1893 Feb 12 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - "Vol XXIII", 1893 Feb 13-1893 Apr 24 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - "Vol XIV", 1893 Apr 25-1893 Jun 25 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - "Vol XXV", 1893 Jun 26-1893 Aug 28 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - "Vol XXVI", 1893 Aug 28-1893 Oct 30 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - "Vol XXVII", 1893 Oct 31-1893 Dec 19 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - "Vol XXVIII", 1893 Dec 20-1894 Feb 24 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - "Vol XXIX", 1894 Feb 25-1894 May 27 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Journal, 1895 Aug-Dec (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Journal, 1896 Jan 1-13, Jun-Dec (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Journal, 1897 Jan-Apr 4 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - "Vol I", "Vol II", 1897 Apr 6-1897Jun 17 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - ''Vol III'', ''Vol IV'', 1897 Jun 18-1897 Oct 22 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - "Vol V", "Vol VI", 1897 Oct 23-1898 Jan 17 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - "Vol VII", 1898 Jan 18-Apr, Nov-Dec (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Journal, 1899 Aug - 1900 Jan 2 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Journal, 1900 Jan 3 - Jun 16 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Journal, 1900 Jun 17 - Oct 15 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Journal, 1900 Oct 15 – 1901 Mar 7 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Journal, 1901 Mar 8 - Jun 9 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Journal, 1901 Jun 15 - Oct (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Journal, 1901 Nov - 1902 Mar 25 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - 1902 Mar 27-1915 Jul 18 1902 Mar 27-1915 Jul 18 1902 Mar 27-1915 Jul 18 (Box 10, Folder 48-65)
    - 1915 Jul 29-Nov 18 1915 Jul 29-Nov 18 1915 Jul 29-Nov 18 (Box 11, Folder 66-67)
    - Electrostatic copies, 1915 Nov 19-1916 Sep 4 (Box 11, Folder 68-71)
    - Miscellaneous entries, no year (Box 11, Folder 72-78)
    - Duplicates: typed, hand-written, 1888 Jan 20-1888 Mar 11, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Fragments, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Clara Hess Foster
    - Electrostatic copies, 1915 Dec-1916 Aug 5 (Box 11, Folder 80-83)
  - Originals--Restricted Circulation
    - John Marshall Foster:, 1916 Nov 19-1915 Dec 16 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - Clara Hess Foster, 1915 Dec 10 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - John Marshall Foster, 1915 Dec 17-1916 Feb 19 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - Clara Hess Foster, 1915 Dec 25-1916 Feb 22 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - John Marshall Foster, 1916 Feb 20-1916 May 20 (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Clara Hess Foster, 1916 Feb 29-1916 May 24 (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - John Marshall Foster, 1916 May 22-1916 Sep 4 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - Clara Hess Foster, 1916 May 30-Aug 5 (Box 11, Folder 87)
- Writings, Series III
  - John Marshall Foster
    - Senior Article, Colby College, 1877 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Sermons: "The Evidence of Christian Experience"; "The Mark of the Beast";"The Reflex Influence of, no date (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Reports: "The Situation at Swatow--Missionaries"; "The Sunday School at Swatow"; "A Last Work"; "Siam", no date (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Report: "Statement Regarding Baptist Work in Siam: The Situation in January, 1909" (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Frank C. Foster
    - Article: "The Southland Revisited", 1956 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Grace Foster
    - Articles: "The Psychotherapy of William James"; "Aspects of Drug Addiction", 1945, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - John Hess Foster
    - Article: "With 'Yale in China"', 1922 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Article: "Physical Examination of Chinese Students", 1923 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Article: "The Vital Capacity of the Chinese", 1923 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Article: "Protein Therapy in Typhoid and Paratyphoid Fever", 1924 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Article: "A Study of the Vital Capacity of the Lungs in the Chinese", 1924 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Article: "Ring Test for Tuberculosis", 1926 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Articles: "Fever in Amoebiasis", "The Liver Diseases of China", (Sermon?): No Title, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Article: "The Practice of Medicine in China and New England with Observations on Hypertension", 1930 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Article: "Hyperpyrexia with Coronary Thrombosis", 1933 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Article: "Amebiasis in Connecticut", 1934 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Article: "Birth Control Issue in Waterbury", 1939 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Article: "Huge Syphilitic Aneurysm: Case Report", 1939 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Article: "Hernia of the Diaphragm ", 1941 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Article: "Aspects of the Narcotic Problem", 1941 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Article: "The World Medical Association in Vienna", 1956 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Article: "Missions and China", "Typhoid and Paratyphoid Fever in Changsha", 1974, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Diaries, 1918, 1919, 1925, 1944-1949 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - "List of Publications", n.d. (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Reports: "Routine Book of the Medical Service 1922-1923, Hunan-Yale Hospital"; "Formulary of Hospital Changsha, China" (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Report: "Ward Routines Part I, Medical Service Hunan-Yale Hospital", n.d. (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Other than by family members
    - Articles and Notes: Medical Subjects, 1926-1973, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Articles: Miscellaneous Subjects, 1872-1953, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Essay by Pete Glazier: "Rev. J.B. Foster", n.d. (Box 19, Folder 26)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, Series IV
  This series contains a wide variety of material that belonged to Elizabeth B. Foster and John Marshall Foster. There are two sequences of material, due to an addendum. The second sequence includes material that might also be classified as Printed Material.
  - Biographical and Organizational Material (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth B. Foster: Party Favors (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Elizabeth B. Foster: Handwritten Poems (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Elizabeth B. Foster: Recipes (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Elizabeth B. Foster: W.C.T.U. Notes (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Elizabeth B. Foster: Religious Exercise Book (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Elizabeth B. Foster: Financial Records- Estate of John Barton Foster, Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Maps (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Maps (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Legal Documents: Writ (1865), Teaching Certificate (1878) (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Material Written or Printed in Chinese (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Furniture Plans Designed by John Marshall Foster (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Souvenirs from voyage of John and Helen Foster to Shanghai on SS. President McKinley, book of verse clippings from A.M. Thomas, 1924, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Photographs: The Foster Family (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Photographs: The Foster Family, Adele M. Fielde (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Photographs of Thomas family, Helen Thomas Foster, John Hess Foster, children, 1896-1955, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Photographs: Groups of People in China (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Photographs: Swatow, China (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Photographs: China, Thailand (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Photographs: U.S.A. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Photographs: U.S.A. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Photograph Album (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - "Our Foster Family - A Genealogical and Biographical Study"(1974) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Genealogical Material (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Material: J.B. Foster (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Notes: John Marshall Foster (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Material: Mr. and Mrs. John Marshall Foster incl. notes re: Adele Fielde (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Material: Anna E. Foster (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Biographical Material: Frank C. Foster (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Biographical Material: Grace R. Foster - Autobiography, edited by John T. Foster (1988) (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Biographical Material: John Hess Foster: Random Recollections and Reminiscences, Part One (1891-1900); "Changsha Memories"- an oral interview with John T. Foster by Marilyn Starr (1980); Random Recollections and Reminiscences, Part Three (1911-1920):"Helen Odiorne Thomas, My Wife, and the Thomas Family," by John H. Foster (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Biographical Material: John T. Foster: "China Up and Down - 1919-1943" (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Certificates and Documents - JMF (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Certificates and Documents - JHF (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Certificate of Disinfection or of Noninfection (1927) - JHF (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Financial Material - JHF (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Financial Material - JMF, Account Book - Waterville, Maine, 1928-1940 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Health Record - Dr. and Mrs. JHF (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - A Directory of the American and European Community Changsha, China, 1925-1926 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Flag of Taiwan (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Map: China, Changsha, Mission Fields of Northern Baptist in China (1940), Showing Mission Stations (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Material re: Faculty Tennis Club (1921-1926) (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Material Written or Printed in Chinese (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Misc. incl. Pamphlets, Program, Material re: Adele Fielde (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Photographs: Clara Hess Foster (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Photographs: Family and Friends in China (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Photographs: Foster Family (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Photographs: Foster Family (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Photographs: Foster Home in China (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Photograph: Great Wall of China near Nankow Pass (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Photographs: Groups of People in China (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Photographs: Misc. incl. Hurricane of 1938 in New Haven (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Photographs: Scenes and Groups of People in China (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Photographs: Scenes in China (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Photograph: Students at Lingnan University, 1927 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Photographs: Used in "Our Foster Family" (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Postcards (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Photograph: Yale-in-China personnel, Atterburg Chapel, 1923 Jun (Box 21, Folder 34)
- Printed Material, 1853-1920; Series V
  Printed Material includes magazine and newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and programs related to the Foster family. A section of books, which includes a Chinese hymnal, a Greek Testament, a workbook of the Chinese language, possibly written by Adele M. Fielde, and the Historical Sketch of the South China Mission by Lida Scott Ashmore, is located at the end of this series.
  - Newspaper: Zion's Advocate, 1853 Jun 17 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper: Linfield College Bulletin, 1973 Jul (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets and Programs Re: Religious Topics (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets and Programs Re: Academic Topics (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets and Programs Re: Miscellaneous Topics (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Written by John Marshall Foster (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings Re: Religious Topics (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings Re: Religious Topics (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings Re: Centralia and Vashon Island, Washington, U.S.A. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings Re: Miscellaneous Topics (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Magazine Clippings Re: Miscellaneous Topics (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Obituaries and Miscellaneous Re: John Barton Foster and John Marshall Foster (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Books: Greek Testament of John M. Foster (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Books: Chinese hymnal of John M. Foster (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Books: The Review, McMinnville College, 1911 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Books: The Review, McMinnville College, 1912 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Books: Historical Sketch of the South China Mission of the American Baptist Foreign Missionary Society, 1860-1920, by Lida Scott Ashmore (Box 16, Folder 17)